Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katrin and if you've been listening to our recent lessons, you know that we've
我是Katrin，如果你一直在听我们最近的课程，你会知道我们
been talking a lot about food.
一直在聊很多关于食物的话题。
That's right and today we have another lesson all about food from a different country.
没错，今天我们有另一节课，全是关于来自不同国家的食物。
Last time we took a look at Mexican food, Chinese food.
上次我们看了墨西哥菜、中国菜。
Now we are talking about Indian food.
现在我们聊的是印度菜。
Okay, Indian food is very famous for being spicy but not all of it is spicy.
好的，印度菜以辛辣闻名，但并非所有菜都辣。
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue and find out just what kinds of food you will
让我们听听今天的对话，看看你在印度餐厅会
find at an Indian restaurant.
发现哪些食物。
So where is this mystery restaurant that we're going to?
那么我们要去的这家神秘餐厅在哪里？
It's an Indian restaurant.
是一家印度餐厅。
I know you have never had Indian food so I thought you might want to try it.
我知道你从没吃过印度菜，所以我想你可能想试试。
That sounds great.
听起来不错。
I am craving some type of beef dish.
我很想吃点牛肉菜。
Well Indian cuisine actually doesn't serve beef.
嗯，印度菜其实不供应牛肉。
You see cows are a sacred animal, a very important element in the Hindu religion so beef is not
你看，牛是神圣的动物，是印度教中非常重要的元素，所以牛肉不
eaten.
被食用。
I see.
我明白了。
So what are we having?
那我们吃什么？
Chicken?
鸡肉？
There are many amazing dishes to choose from.
有很多美味的菜肴可以选择。
We can have some chicken tikka masala which is an amazing curry.
我们可以吃一些鸡肉提卡玛萨拉，这是一种很棒的咖喱。
It's a bit spicy but I think you can handle it.
有点辣，但我觉得你能应付。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
I've always heard that Indian spices give a rich flavor to food.
我一直听说印度香料给食物增添了浓郁的风味。
Yeah.
是的。
Also we can have some naan bread which is baked in a tandoori oven.
我们还可以吃一些在坦都里烤炉里烤的馕饼。
Since you don't use any utensils to eat, you can use this bread to scoop up the curry or
既然你不用任何餐具吃饭，你可以用这个饼来舀咖喱或
rice.
米饭。
What about veggies?
蔬菜呢？
Oh they have a good variety of vegetable based dishes like palak paneer, vegetable samosas
哦，他们有很多种蔬菜为主的菜肴，比如菠菜奶酪、蔬菜萨莫萨
or dal.
或豆汤。
It all sounds so exquisite.
听起来都那么精致。
I can't wait.
我等不及了。
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at a couple of words and phrases here on Language
好的，我们回来了，现在让我们看看语言要点中的
Takeaway.
一些单词和短语。
In this first Language Takeaway today, we have words that are about the kinds of food
在今天的第一个语言要点中，我们有关于我们今天吃的食物种类的
we're eating today.
单词。
So the first one, the character said, I am craving some type of beef.
所以第一个，角色说，我很想吃点牛肉。
So to crave something.
所以“to crave something”。
Okay so that is a verb, to crave and that means that you have a desire, you really want
好的，这是一个动词，“to crave”，意思是你有欲望，你非常想
to eat something, to have a particular thing.
吃某样东西，拥有某个特定的东西。
That's right but it's particular so it's something specific.
没错，但它是特定的，所以是具体的东西。
For example, pregnant women are famous for craving strange foods like pickles.
例如，孕妇以渴望奇怪的食物而闻名，比如泡菜。
Yeah exactly.
是的，没错。
So if you say I'm craving some ice cream, you specifically want ice cream or maybe vanilla
所以如果你说“我很想吃冰淇淋”，你特别想要冰淇淋，或者可能是香草
ice cream.
冰淇淋。
Exactly.
没错。
And this person wants beef but unfortunately there's no beef at Indian restaurants because
这个人想要牛肉，但不幸的是印度餐厅没有牛肉，因为
cows are what?
牛是什么？
Cows are a sacred animal so they are sacred in India.
牛是神圣的动物，所以它们在印度是神圣的。
Sacred means special or somehow important in a religious way.
“Sacred”意思是特殊的，或者在宗教方面很重要的。
For example, you could say this is a very sacred place so please don't use cameras or
例如，你可以说这是一个非常神圣的地方，所以请不要用相机或
phones and take your shoes off.
手机，并脱掉鞋子。
That's right.
没错。
So the word sacred refers to something that is religious and very important for that religion.
所以“sacred”这个词指的是宗教性的，并且对该宗教非常重要的东西。
Especially in this occasion we're talking about the Hindu religion.
特别是在这个场合，我们在谈论印度教。
Okay so the Hindu religion or Hinduism is a religion that's widely practiced in the
好的，所以印度教或印度教是一种在世界范围内广泛实践的
world and maybe most commonly found in India.
宗教，可能最常见于印度。
So you'll see a lot of Hindu temples in India and people don't eat beef like we said because
所以你在印度会看到很多印度教寺庙，人们不吃牛肉，就像我们说的，因为
cows are sacred in the Hindu religion.
牛在印度教中是神圣的。
That's right.
没错。
Okay so now in India or for Indian food, it's common to not use any type of utensil to eat.
好的，所以在印度或印度菜中，通常不使用任何餐具吃饭。
Okay so you might be wondering what is a utensil?
好的，你可能想知道什么是“utensil”？
I know forks, I know spoons.
我知道叉子，我知道勺子。
Well utensil is the word that describes all forks, spoons and knives, things that you
嗯，“utensil”是描述所有叉子、勺子和刀子的词，是你
eat with.
吃饭用的东西。
Okay so utensils are tools for eating and it's a very general category.
好的，所以“utensils”是吃饭的工具，这是一个很广泛的类别。
Right exactly.
对，没错。
So utensils are spoons, forks, knives, everything.
所以“utensils”是勺子、叉子、刀子，所有东西。
Chopsticks are utensils even.
筷子也算餐具。
Okay very good.
好的，很好。
And now since we don't use any utensils, you usually eat with your hand and you scoop up
既然我们不用任何餐具，你通常用手吃饭，你舀起
the food, the rice or the curry.
食物、米饭或咖喱。
Okay to scoop up, this is a verb and usually you use your hands to scoop something.
好的，“to scoop up”，这是一个动词，通常你用手来舀东西。
So in this case I can use a piece of bread to scoop up or to pick up some food.
所以在这种情况下，我可以用一块饼来舀起或捡起一些食物。
That's right.
没错。
To scoop up, it usually means that you somehow make a little bowl or a little figure with
“To scoop up”，通常意味着你用手做成一个小碗或小形状，
your hand so that the liquid or the food will fit inside, kind of like a little scoop.
这样液体或食物就能放进去，有点像一个小勺子。
Or a little cup, that's right.
或者一个小杯子，没错。
So to scoop up, scoop something up.
所以是“舀起来”，把某物舀起来。
Alright so now let's go back, let's review this dialogue and when we come back we're
好了，现在我们回顾一下，复习这段对话，等我们回来之后，
going to take a look at the specific Indian dishes found in this dialogue.
我们会看看这段对话中提到的具体印度菜肴。
So where is this mystery restaurant that we're going to?
那么我们要去的这家神秘餐厅在哪里？
It's an Indian restaurant.
是一家印度餐厅。
I know you have never had Indian food so I thought you might want to try it.
我知道你从来没吃过印度菜，所以我想你可能想试试。
That sounds great.
听起来不错。
I am craving some type of beef dish.
我想吃某种牛肉菜。
Well Indian cuisine actually doesn't serve beef.
嗯，印度菜其实不供应牛肉。
You see cows are a sacred animal, a very important element in the Hindu religion so beef is not
你知道，牛是神圣的动物，在印度教中是非常重要的元素，所以牛肉是不
eaten.
吃的。
I see.
我明白了。
So what are we having?
那我们吃什么？
Chicken?
鸡肉？
There are many amazing dishes to choose from.
有很多美味的菜肴可以选择。
We can have some chicken tikka masala which is an amazing curry.
我们可以吃一些鸡肉提卡玛萨拉，这是一种很棒的咖喱。
It's a bit spicy but I think you can handle it.
有点辣，但我觉得你能应付。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
I've always heard that Indian spices give a rich flavor to food.
我一直听说印度香料给食物增添了浓郁的风味。
Yeah.
是啊。
We can have some naan bread which is baked in a tandoori oven.
我们可以吃一些在坦都里烤炉里烤的馕饼。
Since you don't use any utensils to eat, you can use this bread to scoop up the curry or
既然你不用任何餐具吃饭，你可以用这个饼来舀咖喱或
rice.
米饭。
What about veggies?
那蔬菜呢？
Oh they have a good variety of vegetable based dishes like palak paneer, vegetable samosas
哦，他们有很多种蔬菜类菜肴，比如菠菜奶酪、蔬菜萨莫萨
or dal.
或豆汤。
It all sounds so exquisite.
听起来都那么精致。
I can't wait.
我等不及了。
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at those dishes on Language Takeaway Part
好了，我们回来了，现在让我们看看语言学习第二部分中的那些菜肴。
2.
Oh Marco these lessons are making me so hungry.
哦，马可，这些课让我好饿。
We've been doing them for a couple of weeks now and this one is no exception.
我们已经做了几个星期了，这一课也不例外。
We talked a little bit today about chicken dishes and vegetable dishes but a very general
今天我们聊了一点鸡肉菜和蔬菜菜，但印度菜中一种非常普遍的
kind of dish in Indian food is a curry.
菜肴是咖喱。
That's right a curry.
没错，咖喱。
Now this is a naan and it's a dish that has a variety of spices in it.
现在这是一种馕饼，它是一种含有多种香料的菜肴。
That's right.
没错。
So there are many different flavors not just one flavor.
所以有很多不同的味道，不只是单一味道。
You can have chicken curries and vegetable curries and mutton or lamb curries but the
你可以有鸡肉咖喱、蔬菜咖喱、羊肉咖喱，但
thing that you need to remember in Indian food is that there's usually different colors
在印度菜中你需要记住的是，通常有不同颜色的
of curry.
咖喱。
Red, yellow or green curries.
红咖喱、黄咖喱或绿咖喱。
That's right.
没错。
Exactly.
正是。
So the dishes are usually called curries and an example of a curry we have a chicken tikka
所以这些菜肴通常被称为咖喱，咖喱的一个例子是鸡肉提卡
masala curry.
玛萨拉咖喱。
Okay so we know that there's chicken in it and tikka means that it's grilled chicken
好的，所以我们知道里面有鸡肉，提卡意思是烤鸡肉，
and masala is the name of the spice or the curry, the spice that's in that curry.
玛萨拉是那种咖喱中香料或咖喱的名字。
Exactly.
正是。
So a curry is kind of like a thick sauce with pieces of chicken in it.
所以咖喱有点像一种浓稠的酱汁，里面夹着鸡肉块。
In this case for the chicken tikka masala.
在这个例子中，就是鸡肉提卡玛萨拉。
It's a little bit spicy and it's a color red.
它有点辣，颜色是红色的。
Alright so we've got the chicken tikka masala or masala and usually you eat this with rice
好了，我们有鸡肉提卡玛萨拉，通常你会配米饭
or bread but in India there's a special, there are many different kinds of bread but the
或面包吃，但在印度有一种特别的，有很多种面包，但
special bread we heard today was called naan bread.
我们今天听到的那种特别面包叫做馕饼。
Right naan bread and it's just basically a type of bread.
对，馕饼，它基本上就是一种面包。
Now it's not like the bread that you usually have at home.
它不像你通常在家吃的面包。
It's a flat bread so it kind of looks like a pancake almost.
它是一种扁平面包，所以看起来几乎像煎饼。
It does.
确实。
It's not fluffy.
它不蓬松。
It's flat and the way they cook it is they use this special oven and they cook it inside
它是扁平的，他们烹饪它的方式是用一种特殊的烤炉，在里面烤
the oven.
制。
Now the question is what is that oven called Marco?
现在问题是，那个烤炉叫什么，马可？
That's right.
没错。
The oven that we heard is a tandoori oven.
我们听到的烤炉是坦都里烤炉。
Okay so tandoori is just the name of this oven.
好的，所以坦都里就是这个烤炉的名字。
It's also a style of cooking in India and it's actually one of my favorite kinds of
它也是印度的一种烹饪风格，实际上是我最喜欢的印度菜之一，
Indian food because you have this, these many different kinds of grilled meats.
因为你有这些，很多种不同的烤肉。
You can have tandoori chicken, tandoori mutton, things like that.
你可以有坦都里鸡肉、坦都里羊肉之类的。
Exactly.
正是。
So a tandoori oven is a type of oven usually made from clay.
所以坦都里烤炉是一种通常由粘土制成的烤炉。
That's why it's called tandoori.
这就是为什么它叫坦都里。
Now towards the end we also have some vegetarian options because as we heard in India they
在最后，我们还有一些素食选择，因为正如我们在印度听到的，他们
don't eat beef and many people are also vegetarians.
不吃牛肉，很多人也是素食者。
They don't eat any type of meat at all.
他们根本不吃任何肉类。
So the first vegetable based dish that we heard is a palak paneer.
所以我们听到的第一种蔬菜类菜肴是菠菜奶酪。
That's interesting actually because paneer is curd or like a cheese type of thing.
这其实很有趣，因为奶酪是凝乳或类似奶酪的东西。
So it's usually white and comes in rectangles and paneer you can have many different flavors
所以它通常是白色的，呈矩形，奶酪可以有多种不同的口味，
of it but paneer generally is a kind of a cheese, like a cottage cheese.
但奶酪通常是一种奶酪，像农家奶酪。
That's right.
没错。
And palak is actually spinach so it's a dish that it kind of looks like a thick sauce,
而 palak 其实就是菠菜，所以这道菜看起来像一种浓稠的酱汁，
green sauce which is made out of spinach and within it it has little pieces of this type
一种用菠菜制成的绿色酱汁，里面还有小块这种
of cheese.
奶酪。
I love this dish.
我喜欢这道菜。
It's very very delicious.
非常非常好吃。
We also have vegetable samosas.
我们还有蔬菜咖喱角。
Now a samosa, what's that?
那么咖喱角，那是什么？
Now this is a great dish.
这道菜很棒。
This is often used as an appetizer or as a snack.
它通常用作开胃菜或小吃。
You see these on carts or on the street in India.
在印度，你可以在手推车或街头看到它们。
Now samosas are like pyramids or triangles and inside they have vegetables.
咖喱角像金字塔或三角形，里面包着蔬菜。
So you can have potatoes and peas or lentils, no not lentils, you can have potatoes and
所以你可以放土豆和豌豆或扁豆，不，不是扁豆，你可以放土豆和
peas and they're a little bit crunchy on the outside and soft on the inside and they're
豌豆，它们外面有点脆，里面很软，而且
very tasty.
非常美味。
I guess the equivalent would be to, it's something like an egg roll.
我想它的类似物就是，有点像蛋卷。
Like a dumpling.
像饺子一样。
Like a dumpling because it is deep fried.
像饺子一样，因为它是油炸的。
And we also have dal.
我们还有豆糊。
So this is actually a type of lentil as you mentioned.
所以这实际上是你提到的一种扁豆。
That's right.
没错。
So dal is a lentil dish and it can be flavored in different ways but basically lentils are
所以豆糊是一道扁豆菜，可以用不同方式调味，但基本上扁豆是
these very very very very small round things.
这些非常非常非常小的圆形东西。
They're very good for your health.
它们对你的健康非常好。
And dal is a kind of a soupy lentil dish.
而豆糊是一种像汤一样的扁豆菜。
That's right.
没错。
So lentil is the category of this type of, I don't know if it's, it's not a grain.
所以扁豆是这类东西的类别，我不知道它是不是，它不是谷物。
It's a legume.
它是一种豆类。
It's a legume exactly.
正是豆类。
So it may sound a little bit weird but we'll post some pictures of different types of lentils
所以这可能听起来有点奇怪，但我们会贴一些不同种类扁豆的图片，
because it's like saying potatoes.
因为这就像说土豆一样。
There are many different types of potatoes.
有很多不同种类的土豆。
Sweet potato and all this.
红薯之类的。
And the same thing goes with lentils.
扁豆也是一样。
So we'll post some pictures so you can see what it looks like.
所以我们会贴一些图片，这样你就能看到它长什么样。
But now why don't we go back.
但现在我们为什么不回去呢。
Let's listen to the dialogue again.
让我们再听一遍对话。
Let's review everything and we'll be right back.
让我们回顾一下所有内容，我们马上回来。
So where is this mystery restaurant that we're going to?
那么我们要去的这家神秘餐厅在哪里？
It's an Indian restaurant.
这是一家印度餐厅。
I know you have never had Indian food so I thought you might want to try it.
我知道你从未吃过印度菜，所以我想你可能想试试。
That sounds great.
听起来不错。
I am craving some type of beef dish.
我想吃某种牛肉菜。
Well Indian cuisine actually doesn't serve beef.
嗯，印度菜实际上不供应牛肉。
You see cows are a sacred animal, a very important element in the Hindu religion.
你知道，牛是神圣的动物，是印度教中非常重要的元素。
So beef is not eaten.
所以不吃牛肉。
I see.
我明白了。
So what are we having?
那我们吃什么？
Chicken?
鸡肉？
There are many amazing dishes to choose from.
有很多美味的菜肴可以选择。
We can have some chicken tikka masala which is an amazing curry.
我们可以吃一些鸡肉咖喱，这是一道很棒的咖喱菜。
It's a bit spicy but I think you can handle it.
有点辣，但我觉得你能应付。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
I've always heard that Indian spices give a rich flavor to food.
我一直听说印度香料给食物增添了浓郁的风味。
Yeah.
是的。
We can have some naan bread which is baked in a tandoori oven.
我们可以吃一些在泥炉里烤的馕饼。
Since you don't use any utensils to eat, you can use this bread to scoop up the curry or
既然你不用餐具吃，你可以用这个饼来舀咖喱或
rice.
米饭。
What about veggies?
蔬菜呢？
Oh they have a good variety of vegetable based dishes like palak paneer, vegetable samosas
哦，他们有各种各样的蔬菜菜肴，比如菠菜奶酪、蔬菜咖喱角
or dal.
或豆糊。
It all sounds so exquisite.
听起来都那么精致。
I can't wait.
我等不及了。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So Indian food has a reputation of being spicy but it's very very delicious.
所以印度菜以辣闻名，但非常非常好吃。
That's right.
没错。
And you know what people always tell me, at least my Indian friends always tell me, is
你知道人们总是告诉我什么，至少我的印度朋友总是告诉我，
that saying Indian food is like saying Chinese food.
就是说印度菜就像说中国菜一样。
We have some general idea but every different part of India has its own special foods.
我们有一些大致概念，但印度的每个不同地区都有自己特色的食物。
That's right.
没错。
And so what we get in America at Indian restaurants might not be the same as what we get at Indian
所以我们在美国的印度餐厅吃到的可能和我们在印度的印度餐厅
restaurants in India.
吃到的不同。
So I just want to say that.
所以我想说一下这个。
But generally you can find these dishes at any Indian restaurants in America.
但一般来说，你可以在美国的任何印度餐厅找到这些菜。
That's right actually if next time you're in an Indian restaurant or if you ever go,
没错，实际上，下次你去印度餐厅或者如果你去的话，
ask them from what region or what area of India the food is from.
问问他们食物来自印度的哪个地区或区域。
Because it may be Northern Indian cuisine and obviously that is going to be a little
因为可能是北印度菜，显然那会有点
bit different than maybe the Southern.
不同于南印度菜。
I think the Southern is supposed to be spicier.
我觉得南印度菜应该更辣。
Exactly.
正是。
And it's just like in every country.
这就像每个国家的情况一样。
Even in our own home countries, maybe the food from the coast or from the North will
即使在我们自己的国家，来自沿海或北方的食物可能
be different from the South or the Inlands.
会与南方或内陆地区的食物不同。
And I just want to make one more comment.
我只想再补充一点。
One of my favorite things to do that many Indian restaurants offer in America is the
我最喜欢做的一件事，很多印度餐馆在美国提供的就是
lunch buffet.
午餐自助餐。
So a buffet is basically a self-serve of food.
自助餐基本上就是自己取餐。
So the restaurant will put out many different dishes and you can take as much as you want
所以餐馆会摆出很多不同的菜肴，你可以随意取用
of each but you pay one price.
每种菜想吃多少就吃多少，但只付一个价格。
So it's $11.99 or something.
所以大概是11.99美元左右。
That's very, very good.
这非常非常好。
And yeah, so I often do this when I'm home in the States and I just, you know, I get
是的，所以我回美国时经常这样做，就是，你知道，我可以
to pick my favorite dishes and I eat as much as I want.
挑选我最喜欢的菜，然后想吃多少就吃多少。
And actually I think one other thing that's worth mentioning, we didn't mention in the
实际上，我觉得还有一点值得一提，我们在
dialogue but Indian sweets and the tea is very, very good.
对话中没有提到，但印度甜点和茶非常非常好。
The milk tea that they drink in India is delicious and the sweets are very, very good.
他们在印度喝的奶茶很美味，甜点也非常非常好。
That's right.
没错。
They're famous for being very good and not very healthy for you.
它们以好吃但不健康而闻名。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，完全正确。
They're very sweet.
它们非常甜。
If you're in an Indian restaurant, take note.
如果你在印度餐馆，留意一下。
Look for these different things and let us know.
找找这些不同的东西，然后告诉我们。
Do you like to eat Indian food?
你喜欢吃印度菜吗？
If so, what's your favorite dish?
如果喜欢，你最喜欢的菜是什么？
All right.
好了。
So we'll see you guys at our website EnglishPod.com and until next time.
那我们就在我们的网站EnglishPod.com上见，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。